Guide to the Bookplate Collection, approximately 1890-1955
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
- SERIES V. Vassar College Library Bookplates
  - Loomis, Gertrude Schoepperle, In memoriam (Folder 26.124)
  - Lown, Clarence, Collection (Folder 26.125)
  - Lutz, Alma (VC 1912), Collection (Folder 26.126)
  - Macadam, Carolyn Farrant (VC 1882), Fund (Goudy type; printed by Todd, 1936; Coggeshall, 1946) (Folder 26.127)
  - MacCracken, Henry Noble, Fund (1925) [supply exhausted] (Folder 26.128)
  - MacCracken, Henry Noble, Fund (designed by Arthur H. Noll) (Folder 26.128)
  - McLeod, Leila Durant, In memory of (designed by Arthur H. Noll) (Folder 26.129)
  - MacMahon, E.L. Geiger (VC 1867), Gift of (Folder 26.130)
  - McMartin, Katherine McMartin (VC 1909) Library Fund (printed by Todd) (Folder 26.131)
  - Magill, Roswell, Gift of (Goudy type, printed by Boggeshall, 1946) (Folder 26.132)
  - Marian, John B., Gift of (Folder 26.133)
  - Mary Ann Collection (designed by Mildred C. Greene, before 1923) (Folder 26.134)
  - Master School of Music Association, Grant to Department of Music (printed by Todd) (Folder 26.135)
  - Milholland, Inez (VC 1909), Memorial fund (Pearson, 1925) (Folder 26.136)
  - Mills, Herbert E., Library fund [no plate] (Folder 26.137)
  - Mineah Memorial Fund (printed by Todd) [2 variants] (Folder 26.138)
  - Morgenthau, Henry, Gift of (Folder 26.139)
  - Morris Fund [2 variants] (Folder 26.140)
  - Moulton, Charles William, Memorial fund (Folder 26.141)
  - Murphy, Claudia Q. (Folder 26.141a)
  - Music, Department of, Gift Nagai, Shige See: Yamakawa, Stematz (Folder 26.142)
  - Not to be taken from the Vassar College Library (Folder 26.143)
  - Nourse, Mary Pemberton (VC 1914), In memory of Oldham, Theodosia See: Class of 1892 (Folder 26.144)
  - Olmsted, Clara Morgan (VC 1876), In memory of (Goudy type; printed by Coggeshall, 1946) (Folder 26.145)
  - Palmer, Elizabeth Hatch, Gift of Peabody Fund [no plate] (Folder 26.146)
  - Pell, Herbert Claiborne, Gift of (Folder 26.147)
  - Penrose, Katharine Drexel (VC 1889), Fund (printed by Todd, 1934) (Folder 26.148)
  - Penrose, Katharine Drexel (VC 1889), Bequest of (Folder 26.149)
  - Philadelphia Vassar Club, Gift of (Folder 26.150)
  - Philalethean Society (Folder 26.151)
  - Pickard, Matthew W., Gift of (Goudy type, printed by Coggeshall, 1946) (Folder 26.152)
  - Platt, Hon. Edmund, Gift of (Folder 26.153)
  - Pratt, Charles M., Gift of (Folder 26.154)
  - Putnam, Helen Gates, Endowment Fund for Conservation (Goudy type, printed by Kalkoff Press, 1942) (Folder 26.155)
  - Raymond, John H., From the library of (Folder 26.156)
  - Raymond House (designed by Merrymount Press) (Folder 26.157)
  - Raymond Room (designed by Edith Irving; engraved by W.F. Hopson, 1912) (Folder 26.158)
  - Richey Biology Fund (printed by Todd) (Folder 26.159)
  - Rockefeller Library Fund (printed by Rudge, 1936) (Folder 26.160)
  - Rogers, Dr. Cornelia H.B., From the library of (Folder 26.161)
  - Rose, Elaine Wolf (VC 1922), Gift of (Folder 26.162)
  - Rose W.K., Collection (Folder 26.163)
  - Roselli, Bruno, Gift of (Folder 26.164)
  - Rossbach, Mabel L. (Folder 26.165)
  - Salmon, Lucy M., Bequest of (1927) [2 variants] (Folder 26.166)
  - Salmon, Lucy M., In memory of, Gift of D.M. Eidlitz (Folder 26.167)
  - Salmon, Lucy M., [personal] (designed by E.D. French) (Folder 26.168)
  - Sanford, William M., Gift of, 1901 (Folder 26.169)
  - Scott, Mary Augusta (VC 1876), Foundation of (designed by A.H. Noll) (Folder 26.170)
  - Sharpe, Sally Patterson, In memory of (designed by Helen Patterson Williams; plate lost when Rudge plant was sold) (Folder 26.171)
  - Sharpe, Sally Patterson, In memory of (Folder 26.171)
  - Shattuck, George Burbank, Gift of (Folder 26.172)
  - Sherwood, Margaret Pollock See: Class of 1886 Fund
  - Slavonic Library Fund [no plate] (Folder 26.173)
  - Sleight, Josephine Wheeler (VC 1898), Memorial to (Folder 26.174)
  - Smith, Winifred, Gift of (used with VCL label) (Folder 26.175)
  - Snyder, Alice D. (VC 1909), From the library of (with Edith Emerson drawing of library with pine tree; reproduced by Meridan Gravure Co.) (Folder 26.176)
  - Speidel, Elizabeth McLure (VC 1906), In memory of (designed and printed by Yale University Press) (Folder 26.177)
  - Stimson, Dorothy (VC 1912), Gift of (Folder 26.178)
  - Stokes, Emma Hartley, Memorial to Stearns, Edith Helen See: Class of 1892 (Folder 26.179)
  - Storer, Elizabeth Drinker (VC 1870), Memorial Fund (printed by Rudge; later by Yale) (Folder 26.180)
  - Strelsky, Nikander, From the library of (Folder 26.181)
  - Strelsky, Nikander, [personal] (Folder 26.182)
  - Students' Subscription Fund (Folder 26.183)
  - Swan, Mrs. Cyrus, In memory of (Folder 26.184)
  - Taft, William Howard, In memory of (Folder 26.185)
  - Taylor, James Monroe, Fund (designed by Sidney L. Smith) (Folder 26.186)
  - Thallon, Ida Carleton (VC 1897), Gift of (Folder 26.187)
  - Thomas, Mary Rogers (VC ex-1926) (Folder 26.188)
  - Thompson, F.F., Memorial, Gift of (designed and engraved by Robert Eunson) (Folder 26.189)
  - Thompson, Mary Clark, Bequest of (Folder 26.190)
  - Thompson, Mary Clark, [personal] (Folder 26.190)
  - Thompson, Mary Clark, Fund (printed by Rudge) (Folder 26.191)
  - Thompson, Mary Thaw (VC 1877), Gift of (Folder 26.192)
  - Thompson, Virginia See: Bryson, Ella Fitzgerald
  - Tillinghast, Isabel Nelson (VC 1878), In memory of (Folder 26.193)
  - Toof, Elizabeth Fox (VC 1913), From the library of (Folder 26.194)
  - Townson, Andrew D., Gift of (Folder 26.195)
  - Tucker, Martha Sharpe (VC 1883) See: Jenckes, Harriet Morse
  - Turgenev Collection, Gift of Class of 1882 (Folder 26.196)
  - Turgenev [personal plate]
  - Twyeffort, Dorothy (VC 1930), Gift to the Department of French (Folder 26.197)
  - Underhill, Adelaide, Gift of (Folder 26.198)
  - Underhill, Adelaide, In memory of (designed by Merrymount Press, 1938) (Folder 26.198)
  - Underhill, Adelaide, Bequest of (printed by Rudge, 1936) (Folder 26.198)
  - Underhill, Adelaide [personal plate] (Folder 26.198)
  - Vassar, John Guy, Art Fund (printed by Rudge, 1938) (Folder 26.199)
  - Vassar Alumnae Historical Association (engraved by E.D. French, 1896) (Folder 26.200)
  - Vassar Alumnae House Library (Folder 26.200a)
  - Vassar Brothers Institute, Gift of (Folder 26.202)
  - Vassar College House Libraries (Folder 26.203)
  - Vassar College House Libraries, In memory of... (Folder 26.203)
  - Vassar College House Libraries, Gift of... (Folder 26.203)
  - Vassar College House Li braries (Folder 26.203)
  - See also: Cushing, Florence M,, Fund (Folder 26.203)
  - Vassar College Library (without border; printed by Artcraft Press, 1931) (Folder 26.203)
  - Vassar College Library (with line border; printed by Kalkoff Press, 1940) (Folder 26.204)
  - Vassar College Library (without border; printed by Rudge, 1932, 1935) (Folder 26.204)
  - Vassar College Library (small, narrow; printed by Kalkhoff Press, 1940) (Folder 26.205)
  - Vassar College Library (smallest; printed by Kalkhoff Press, 1940) (Folder 26.206)
  - Vassar College Library (with line border; printed by Elm Tree Press, 1948) (Folder 26.207)
  - Vassar College Library (without border, n.d.) (Folder 26.208)
  - Vassar College Library (made without ownership line for student use; 1935?) (Folder 26.209)
  - Vassar College Library - F.F. Thompson Building (with original Vassar College seal) (Folder 26.210)
  - Vassar College Library (with small Vassar College seal redrawn by Hood in1930) (Folder 26.211)
  - Vassar College Library, Bequest of... (Folder 26.212)
  - Vassar College Library, Ex libris (with reproduction of wood engraving of library by Ruzicka; process reprint) (Folder 26.213)
  - Vassar College Library, From the library of (Folder 26.214)
  - Vassar College Library, Gift of (pre-1927) (Folder 26.215)
  - Vassar College Library, Gift of, (various; 1930's) (Folder 26.216)
  - Vassar College Library, Gift of (with line border; printed by Yew Ridge Press, 1937; Yale, 1939?) (Folder 26.217)
  - Vassar College Library, Gift of (with line border; printed by Elm Tree Press, 1944) (Folder 26.218)
  - Vassar College Library, Gift of (small; Goudy type; printed by Coggeshall, 1946) (Folder 26.219)
  - Vassar College Library, Gift of (Elm Tree Press, 1948) (Folder 26.220)
  - Vassar College Library, Gift of (Sequoia Press, 1951, 1954?) (Folder 26.221)
  - Vassar College Library, Gift of (with line border, n.d.) (Folder 26.222)
  - Vassar College Library, Gift of (with Emerson drawing of library with pine tree; reproduced by Meridan Gravure Co., 1942) (Folder 26.223)
  - Vassar College Library, Gift of (designed by Robert Eunson) See: Thompson, F.F., Memorial, Gift of (Folder 26.223)
  - Vassar College Library, Gift of (with conventionalized view of library between trees; engraved by Ralph Pearson, 1925) (Folder 26.224)
  - Vassar College Library, Gift of Publisher [various] (Folder 26.225)
  - Vassar College Library, In memory of... (Folder 26.226)
  - Vassar College Library, Purchased from... (Folder 26.227)
  - Vassar College Library, With the compliments of.. (Folder 26.228)
  - Victory, S.S. Vassar (1945) (Folder 26.229)
  - Wagar, Effie Serena, Fund (Goudy type; printed by Coggeshall, 1946) (Folder 26.230)
  - Walworth, Reubena H. (VC 1896), Fund (engraved by Ralph Pearson, 1925; same design for Class of 1899 Fund) (Folder 26.231)
  - Walworth, Reubena H. (VC 1896), Memorial to (Folder 26.231)
  - Warren, Katherine (VC 1889), Gift of (Folder 26.232)
  - Washburn, Margaret Floy (VC 1891), From the library of [with personal plate] (Folder 26.233)
  - Weiss, Anton C., Library Endowment Fund (1940) (Folder 26.234)
  - Wheeler, Jessie F. (VC 1882), Gift of (with Emerson drawing of library; reproduced by Meridan Gravure Co., 1942) (Folder 26.235)
  - Wheeler, Jessie F. (VC 1882), Fund (Folder 26.235)
  - White, Florence Donnell, Bequeathed to Vassar College Department of French (Folder 26.236)
  - Whitman, William W., Gift of, 1900 (Folder 26.237)
  - Whitney, Marian P., Gift of (designed and printed by Yale University Press, 1939) (Folder 26.238)
  - Whitney, Marian P., Gift of (Folder 26.238)
  - Whitney, Marian P., Fund (Folder 26.238)
  - Willard, Willis Bradley, Bequest of (printed by Rudge, 1932) (Folder 26.239)
  - Wood, Francis A., Here and There Fund (designed by W.F. Hopson; large, 1912; small, 1913) (Folder 26.240)
  - Wright, Helen, Collection (printed by Rudge, 1936) (Folder 26.241)
  - Wylie, Laura J., Fund (printed by Todd) (Folder 26.242)
  - Wylie, Laura J., From among the books of (Folder 26.242)
  - Yamakawa, Stematz (VC 1882) (Folder 26.243)
  - General Information: Miscellaneous correspondence and information regarding the Collection (Folder 26.244a)
  - General Information: Paper for bookplates; Press work (Folder 26.244b)
  - General Information: List of suggested samples to send to other libraries (Folder 26.245)
  - General Information: Designers: List of prominent designers (Folder 26.246)
  - General Information: Designers: Armstrong, Margaret (Folder 26.247)
  - General Information: Designers: Artcraft Press (Folder 26.248)
  - General Information: Designers: Bailey, Banks and Biddle Co. (Folder 26.249)
  - General Information: Designers: Bird, Elisha Brown (Folder 26.250)
  - General Information: Designers: Black, Starr and Gorham, Inc. (Folder 26.251)
  - General Information: Designers: Coggeshall, Howard (Folder 26.252)
  - General Information: Designers: Cole, Timothy (Folder 26.253)
  - General Information: Designers: Drela (Folder 26.254)
  - General Information: Designers: Duttons, Inc. (Folder 26.255)
  - General Information: Designers: Elson Co., Inc. (Folder 26.256)
  - General Information: Designers: Emerson, Edith (Folder 26.257)
  - General Information: Designers: Eunson (Folder 26.258)
  - General Information: Designers: French, Edwin D. (Folder 26.259)
  - General Information: Designers: Goudy, Frederic W. (Folder 26.260)
  - General Information: Designers: Greene, Miss Mildred C. (Folder 26.261)
  - General Information: Designers: Hammett, J.L. Co. (Folder 26.262)
  - General Information: Designers: Harbor Press (Folder 26.263)
  - General Information: Designers: Hood, Jennings (Folder 26.264)
  - General Information: Designers: Hopson, Wiliam F (Folder 26.265)
  - General Information: Designers: Irving, Edith (Folder 26.266)
  - General Information: Designers: Kalkhoff Press (Folder 26.267)
  - General Information: Designers: Lansing Broas (Folder 26.268)
  - General Information: Designers: Meridan Gravure Co. (Folder 26.269)
  - General Information: Designers: Merrymount Press (Folder 26.270)
  - General Information: Designers: Noble, G. Curtis (Folder 26.271)
  - General Information: Designers: Noll, Arthur H. (Folder 26.272)
  - General Information: Designers: Pearson, Ralph M. (Folder 26.273)
  - General Information: Designers: Rudge (Folder 26.274)
  - General Information: Designers: Ruzicka (Folder 26.275)
  - General Information: Designers: Scribner See: Armstrong, Margaret
  - General Information: Designers: Smith, Sidney L. (Folder 26.276)
  - General Information: Designers: Todd (Folder 26.277)
  - General Information: Designers: University Press, Sewanee See: Noll, Arthur H.
  - General Information: Designers: Uridge (Folder 26.278)
  - General Information: Designers: Williams, Helen Patterson (Folder 26.279)
  - General Information: Designers: Yale University Press (Folder 26.280)
  - Vassar College Library bookplates (Scrapbook 6)
- SERIES VI. Bookplate Plates
  - Plates for: Timothy Cole bookplate for himself; James H. Weeks Memorial Collection bookplate; Vassar College seal (Jennings Hood) for bookplate (Box 27)